# Yilei Cheng

(046)703752626 yilei.cheng.cyl@gmail.com Björnstigen 125, Stockholm I am a driven and enthusiastic individual who embraces new challenges and seeks to continuously expand my knowledge and skills. I am eager to collaborate with like-minded individuals who are passionate about their work and driven to make a positive impact together.

#### **EDUCATION**

## KTH Royal Institute of Technology, Stockholm, Sweden

August 2019 - June 2022

• Bachelor's degree in Information and Communication Technology

#### **SKILLS**

- Hard: Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, C, C++, HTML, CSS, Storybook, Backstage, Elixir, C#, Python, MySQL, MIPs, DevOps, Machine Learning, Jupyter Notebook, Agile, Website Development, UX Design, User Research, VSCode, Figma, Unity, Unreal Engine 5, Google Analytics, Miro, Jira, Matlab, Git, Excel, Linux, Logisim
- **Soft**: Leadership, Communication, Creative Thinking, Critical Thinking, Problem Solving, Self Reflection, Teamwork, Organization, Flexibility, Fast Learner, Teaching
- Language: English, Chinese, Swedish (Studying)

## **WORK EXPERIENCES**

## Software Engineer Intern at King, Stockholm, Sweden

August 2022 - Current

- Worked as a front-end developer to develop and maintain an internal platform that aimed to increase the observability and discoverability of tools and documentation for internal developers at King.
- Skills: React, TypeScript, CSS, DevOps, Agile, UX Design, Figma, Storybook, Google Analytics, Jira, Git, Web Development, VSCode

## Machine Learning Intern at Automynt AB, Stockholm, Sweden January 2022 - June 2022

- Used my machine learning knowledge to create a classification system that could cluster users based on their spending behaviors. The model was trained using a transactional dataset.
- Skills: Machine Learning, Jupyter Notebook, Python, Communication, Git

## Teaching Assistant at KTH, Stockholm, Sweden

August 2021 - March 2022

- Helped the professors to check and grade labs and seminars for multiple courses such as Digital Design and Embedded Electronics.
- Skills: Communication, Teaching, Organization, Leadership

#### HR and Quality Assistant at GE, Växjö, Sweden

June 2018 - September 2018

- Helped the HR and Quality manager to organize company flowcharts and employment list.
- Skills: Excel, Communication, Organization, Fast Learner

#### **PROJECT EXPERIENCES**

## **Developer Portal**

August 2022 - Current

• A platform for developers at King with the goal of increasing discoverability and observability. It is achieved by the integration of tools used by developers to provide a quick and clean overview and insight into the technologies that exist within the company. The platform is built on top of Spotify's Backstage.

• Skills: React, TypeScript, Storybook, Teamwork, Creative Thinking

#### **Spending Behaviour Classification System**

January 2022 - June 2022

- A machine learning model was created by pipelining multiple existing models. The goal was to implement a budget system to help people build a balance between their income and spending.
- Skills: Machine Learning, Python, Jupyter Notebook, Excel, MySQL

#### Horizonless

June 2021 - September 2021

- An open-world role-playing game with infinitely generated map tiles. The game was inspired by Minecraft and War of Warcraft. Perlin noise was used as the main method for the generation of random tiles. The assets were all created from scratch.
- Skills: Unity, C#, Agile/Scrum, Teamwork, Creative Thinking, Leadership

#### AI Gomoku Game

January 2021 - April 2021

- A traditional board game implemented using Alpha-Beta Pruning with various search depths corresponding to different difficulty levels. It used heuristics to calculate and predict the winning and losing probabilities at different locations in the current state as well as in the future states to make the best-calculated move.
- Skills: Artificial Intelligence, Java, Teamwork, Problem Solving

#### Dog LinkedIn

January 2021 - April 2021

- An Android App developed for all wannabe-dog-owners after investigating the market demands. A simplified and modified version of LinkedIn was created for dog lovers, the platform helped establish connections and provide useful information and various functions.
- Skills: Figma, Communication, User Research, Market Research, Teamwork